<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Projects>
    <Project name="tower">
        <Title>TowerDefense</Title>
        <Subtitle>A tower defense game I made for a school assignment.</Subtitle>
        <Banner>../images/td/banner.png</Banner>
        <YT>https://www.youtube.com/embed/WFg7cGwH0js?t=12</YT>
        <Type>Game</Type>
        <Date>07-09-2021</Date>
        <Software>Unity, Blender, Vscode and PAINT.net</Software>
        <Lang>C#</Lang>
        <Role>Programmer</Role>
        <ShowcaseText>        This was the first school assignment of my second year. 
        In this assignment we had to make a tower defense game.  
        I already had a pretty good idea what I wanted to make. 
        Flying drone and grapple hooks! 
        
        In my game you first play the game as a normal tower defense 
        game, but then you notices that boxes are falling on the 
        playground. You can then go into 'drone mode' and pick them up 
        with your grappling hook an bring it back to base.</ShowcaseText>
        <ShowcaseImg>../images/gif2.gif</ShowcaseImg>
        <Github>https://github.com/PiterGroot/TowerDefense</Github>
    </Project>
    <Project name="sand">
        <Title>Falling Sand Engine</Title>
        <Banner>../images/sand/banner.png</Banner>
        <YT>https://www.youtube.com/embed/REKUA5vgOz8</YT>
        <Subtitle>A falling sand game I originally wrote for a game jam, but decided to work on it alone instead.</Subtitle>
        <Type>Game</Type>
        <Date>23-11-2021</Date>
        <Software>Unity</Software>
        <Lang>C#</Lang>
        <Role>Programmer</Role>
        <ShowcaseText>        Ever played Noita? Well I have, and I loved it. Noita has 
        a really cool mechanic and that is that every pixel on
        the screen is simulated in the physics engine. I made
        a very simple game out of that idea. Falling Sand 
        Engine is a sandbox (no pun intended) game where 
        you van place different elements on the screen. Water 
        flows, fire and lava burns wood ect ect. I think it is
        really fun to play around in this game.</ShowcaseText>
        <ShowcaseImg>../images/gif1.gif</ShowcaseImg>
        <Github>https://github.com/PiterGroot/UnityFallingSandEngine</Github>
    </Project>
    <Project name="worldgen">
        <Title>2D world generation</Title>
        <Banner>../images/worldgen/banner.png</Banner>
        <YT>https://www.youtube.com/embed/REKUA5vgOz8</YT>
        <Subtitle>Containing mountains, infinite terrain and caves!</Subtitle>
        <Type>Game</Type>
        <Date>18-05-2021</Date>
        <Software>Unity</Software>
        <Lang>C#</Lang>
        <Role>Programmer</Role>
        <ShowcaseText>        I think almost every game developer at least once in 
        their live wanted to make a terraria-like game, and so 
        did I. In this prototype I tried to mimick the terraria 
        world generation (caves, terrain and mountains)</ShowcaseText>
        <ShowcaseImg>../images/gif3.gif</ShowcaseImg>
        <Github></Github>
    </Project>
    <Project name="shapr">
        <Title>Shapr</Title>
        <YT>https://www.youtube.com/embed/CkFXxgCNoR0</YT>
        <Banner>../images/shapr/banner.png</Banner>
        <Subtitle>A simplistic 2D dungeon crawler roguelike!</Subtitle>
        <Type>Game</Type>
        <Date>06-04-2022</Date>
        <Software>Unity</Software>
        <Lang>C#</Lang>
        <Role>Programmer</Role>
        <ShowcaseText>        Shapr (*Shaaper) is my first serious commercial game 
        project that im making. It has two of my most favourite
        game genres; Roguelikes and Bullet hells! The idea is 
        that this game is a simplistic dungeon crawler 
        roguelike game. The player has a quick dash to dodge 
        all of the bullets and ofcourse a gun. You have to fight 
        your way through hordes of enemies and slay powerfull 
        bosses. </ShowcaseText>
        <ShowcaseImg>../images/gif4.gif</ShowcaseImg>
        <Github></Github>
    </Project>
    <Project name="water">
        <Title>Water shader</Title>
        <YT>https://www.youtube.com/embed/3U19TpS8N1s</YT>
        <Banner>../images/water/banner.png</Banner>
        <Subtitle>A shader made with shadergraph in Unity.</Subtitle>
        <Type>Game</Type>
        <Date>07-03-2022</Date>
        <Software>Unity</Software>
        <Lang>Shadergraph</Lang>
        <Role>Programmer</Role>
        <ShowcaseText>        This water shader was actually my first shader ever!     
        I am really proud because it uses a lot of interesting 
        tricks and ideas to convey the idea of water. For 
        example it uses the camera depth buffer to calculate 
        how far the camera is from the water.</ShowcaseText>
        <ShowcaseImg>../images/gif5.gif</ShowcaseImg>
        <Github></Github>
    </Project>
</Projects>

